Are you busy?
هل أنت مشغول؟
I'm on leave today.
اليوم إجازة
Is Qin Xiaonan okay?
هل تشين شياو نان بخير؟
He said
قال
he misses you.
اشتقت إليك
Great. Let me tell you.
جيد جدا أقول لك
Fishing there is...
‫هل تصطاد السمك هناك؟
Chen. Do you want to go fishing?
‫تشين، هل تصطاد؟
Let's go together.
‫لنذهب
No.
لن أذهب
Okay, let's go.
حسنا لنذهب
That place...
ذلك المكان
Wait.
انتظر
What?
ماذا حدث
Do you want to go fishing?
هل ستذهب لصيد السمك
Yes.
اذهب
But
حسنًا
I'm okay if I don't.
لا بأس
Go ahead then.
اذهب
It's Chinese New Year.
عيد الربيع
It's rare to be on holiday.
من النادر أن تكون عطلة
Not at all.
ليس نادرا
I've been on winter vacation for a long time.
لقد كنت في عطلة الشتاء لفترة طويلة
Just do as I say.
إذا طلبت منك الذهاب فتذهب
Boys should exercise more.
فتى يجب أن تتحرك أكثر
Come on.
هيا
Bring him to have a nice dinner after fishing.
سآخذه لتناول وجبة جيدة بعد الصيد
No problem.
لا مشكلة
Leave him to us.
سنتولى الأمر
Come back later.
سأعود متأخرا
Okay.
حسنا
Let's go.
‫لنذهب
Chen.
‫تشين
You've been standing here for half an hour.
‫لقد وقفت هنا لمدة نصف ساعة
Aren't you cold?
لا أشعر بالبرد
I'm here.
لقد وصلت
Drive in.
ادخل
Let me take a look at your car.
فحص السيارة لك
Come out.
انزل
I'll drive.
سأفتح
Miss.
يا آنسة
Have you gotten your car fixed?
هل تم إصلاح السيارة التي صدمتها المرة السابقة
Yes, it's fixed. Thank you.
تم إصلاحها   تم إصلاحها   شكرا
It's driving a little crooked.
لقد اختفت قليلاً
The noise is strong too.
صوت الضجيج قوي أيضا
Soda water.
ماء الغاز
Later, I'll check
سأعطيك
your tire pressure
فحص ضغط الجنمة
and wheel alignment
‫قم بالتحديد أربع جولات أخرى‬
before checking the tires.
انظر إلى الإطار
Did it shake very badly
في الصباح
when you warmed up the car this morning?
هل ترتجف بشدة
Not too bad.
لا بأس به
What do you mean?
ما معنى لا بأس به
Didn't you drive this car?
لم تقود السيارة
I don't usually drive.
لا أقود عادة
I go on business trips very often.
دائما في رحلة عمل
Is there a problem?
هل هناك مشكلة
There's a problem with the valve train.
‫مشكلة إغلاق البوابة الهوائية‬
Just drive on the expressway more often
ركض في السرعة العالية أكثر
and it'll sort itself out.
سأكون بخير
You're quite good at lying.
أنت تعرف كيف تخدع الناس
What did I lie to you about?
ما الذي أخدعك؟
Last year, someone fooled me
تم خداعي في العام الماضي
into aligning my tires.
‫وقمت بتحديد موقع أربع جولات‬
Did they mess up?
ألم تقومي بعمل جيد
It's not that they fooled you.
لا يخدعك أحد
It's because of your technique.
المهارة ليست جيدة
Alright.
حسنا
I'll leave it to you.
على أي حال سأترك الأمر لك
Where's Qin Xiaonan?
أين تشين شياو نان؟
He went fishing.
ذهب لصيد السمك
Didn't he say he missed me?
ألم يقل إنه يشتاق إلي؟
He still went fishing.
يصطاد السمك
He's just a kid.
مزاج طفولي
He doesn't remember the things he says.
لقد نسيت بعد الحديث
When will he be back?
متى سيعود
I brought him
أحضرت له
a lot of delicious food.
الكثير من الأطعمة اللذيذة
I don't know.
لا أعرف
He should be back quite late.
يجب أن يكون متأخرًا جدًا
What is this?
ما هذا
Ring spanner.
‫مباركة زهر البرقوق
What about that one?
ماذا عن ذلك
That one.
ذلك
Socket wrench.
‫المصباح‬
What is it for?
ماذا تفعل
It turns
‫هذا مقص‬
the bolts
‫لوح العجلات‬
on tires.
‫يستخدم على عجلة‬
Go in.
ادخل
Don't we need to check the car?
ألا تريد فحص السيارة
We'll do it in the afternoon.
‫سأفعلها بعد الظهر‬
It's too cold in the garage.
إن المصنع بارد جدا
It's warm inside.
لندخل دافئ
Okay.
حسنا
Hello?
ألو
Your son brought a girl
ابنك أحضر امرأة
to the garage.
إلى المصنع
It's messy because of the kid.
‫يعيش الأطفال في فوضى‬
I tried tidying up.
لقد نظفتها بشكل عشوائي
It used to be even messier.
كان منزلك أكثر فوضى في الماضي
I remember the first time
أتذكر أول مرة
I came here,
‏عندما أتيت إلى هنا‏
there was a pile of test papers here.
‏كان هناك سلة من الامتحان‏
I still get scared when I hear the words
‏ما زلت خائفة‏
"test paper."
‏ما زلت خائفة؟‏
I did too many of them in high school.
أخاف من المدرسة الثانوية
Can you understand it?
هل تفهم
Of course.
‏بالطبع‏
It's such a simple question.
هذا السؤال بسيط
I remember that in our time,
‏أتذكر‏
the math papers
ورقة الرياضيات
were carved and printed
‫تم نحتها بأنفسهم
by the teachers themselves.
طبعتها بنفسك
Every time I finished one,
في كل مرة انتهيت
my hand would have blue smudges on it.
الأزرق في يدي
I couldn't even wash them off.
لا يمكن غسلها
Really?
‏حقاً؟‏
I bought my test papers
‏اشتريت ورقة الامتحان‏
at the school gate.
‏اشتريتها عند بوابة المدرسة‏
Our teacher was thrifty.
معلمنا يوفر المال
He carved it all himself.
‫نقش كل شيء بنفسك‬
I remember
أتذكر
my math teacher
معلمنا الرياضيات
was already 60
‫عندما علمنا
when he taught me.
كانت 60 سنة
I wonder how he's doing now.
لا أعرف كيف الوضع الآن
Is he doing well?
هل هذا جيد؟
The first time I saw you
المرة السابقة في محطة الوقود
at the gas station,
في محطة الوقود
I didn't dare to approach you.
لم أجرؤ على التعرف عليك
You still look the same,
ما زال مظهره هكذا
but you've suddenly grown up.
لقد كبرت فجأة
The door is open.
لم يغلق الباب
Lu—
‫لو
I...
أنا أنا
I came back in a hurry
عدت بسرعة
to see Aunt Gui Xiao.
لرؤية العمة جو شياو
It's not enough just to have fish.
لا يمكن السمك فقط
We need vegetables.
لا يزال هناك طبق
Yes.
نعم نعم
Let's go grocery shopping.
لنذهب لشراء الخضروات
Okay.
‫حسناً
Hello, are you looking for Lu Chen?
‫مرحباً هل تبحث عن لو تشين
You are?
‫من أنت
I'm his classmate.
أنا زميله
His ex-classmate.
زملائه السابقين
Auntie, who are you?
‫عمتي، من أنت؟
I’m Lu Chen’s mother.
‫أنا والدة لو تشين
Hello, Auntie.
‫مرحباً يا عمتي
Where is Lu Chen?
‫أين لو تشين
He went out to buy groceries.
‫ذهب لشراء الخضروات
He'll be back soon.
سيعود بعد قليل
He left you here alone
تركك هنا وحدك
to go grocery shopping?
ذهب لشراء الخضروات
Have a seat.
تفضل بالجلوس
I'll wait outside.
سأنتظر بالخارج
It's okay.
لا داعي لا داعي
Sit down.
اجلس
Why don't you sit down?
لماذا لا تجلس
What's your name?
ما اسمك؟
Gui Xiao.
"غوي شياو"
"Gui" as in return, "Xiao" as in dawn.
[شياو في طريق العودة]
Auntie, let me help you.
عمتي، دعيني أساعدك
It's okay.
لا داعي لا داعي
You are our guest.
أنت ضيف
Sit down.
اجلسي
Auntie, I’ll leave you alone.
خالتي، عودي إلى عملك
I need to make a call.
سأخرج لأتصل
Miss.
يا فتاة
Are you cold?
هل تشعرين بالبرد؟
I'm fine. I'm not cold.
لا بأس لا أشعر بالبرد
Here.
تعال
Come side inside.
تفضل بالجلوس
Will I be a bother?
لا أزعجك
I was hoping
أنا أتطلع
someone would come talk to me.
أن يتحدث معي أحد
Sit there. It's warm.
اجلس هناك دافئ
Do you want some tea?
هل تشرب الشاي
No, thanks.
‫لا داعي شكرا
Did you meet Lu Chen through car repair?
‫هل تعرف لو تشين لإصلاح السيارة
No, we were classmates.
‫لا نحن زملاء
Middle school classmates.
‫زميل في المدرسة الإعدادية
Lu Chen, you're here?
‫لو تشين هنا
You bought so many vegetables.
‫اشتريت الكثير من الأطباق
Do you have guests over?
هل ستدفع لنا الطعام؟
Give me a big one.
أريد قطعة كبيرة
Okay.
حسنًا
Give me half a catty
أريد ذلك الجمبري
of prawns.
وزني نصف كيلو
Prawns are expensive
هذه الأيام
these days.
هذا الجمبري باهظ الثمن
It's going to be Chinese New Year soon.
هل هذا عيد الربيع؟ لا
It's expensive for me to get them too.
لقد اشتريت البضائع باهظة الثمن
The price has gone up.
لقد ارتفع السعر
I have no choice.
لا يوجد طريقة
-It’s okay, go ahead. -I'm not scamming you.
لا بأس، يمكنك أن تطلبي
Okay.
حسنا
Give me another one.
أعطني واحدة أخرى
Pick the best one.
اختاري الأفضل
Auntie.
عمتي
You're leaving?
هيا بنا
You're leaving after changing his sheets?
وغير غطاء السرير وغادر
He doesn't want me around.
هذا الشاب غير سعيد لرؤيتي
If it's convenient for you,
إذا كان لديك وقت
come with him to have a meal
تعال معه إلى المنزل
at my house.
تعال لتناول الطعام
Let that kid
و ذلك الطفل
come too.
تعال معنا
I'll let him know when he comes back.
سأخبره عندما يعود
See you.
سأذهب
Take care.
مع السلامة
Why did you come out?
لماذا خرجت
Your mother came just now.
لقد جاءت والدتك للتو
She seemed a little unhappy.
أعتقد أنها غير سعيدة
I was afraid I might say something wrong,
أخشى أن أقول شيئًا خاطئًا
so I came out for a while.
لذا خرجت لأجلس
Did she bully you?
هل أنت غاضب؟
No.
لا
Your mother is nice.
والدتك لطيفة
She even asked Qin Xiaonan and me
طلبت مني أنا و تشين شياو نان
to go eat at your house.
إلى منزلك لتناول الطعام
Are we going?
هل نذهب
Do you want to go?
هل تريد الذهاب
I bought so many things.
اشتريت الكثير من الأشياء
It's a waste if we don't eat them.
‫لا تأكل هذا مضيعة‬
Go on in.
ادخل
If I don't go,
إذا لم تذهب
shouldn't we explain it to her?
هل يجب أن أشرح لها
I think
أعتقد أنها
she really wants you to go back.
تريد أن تعود
It's okay.
لا بأس
I'll talk to her later.
‫سأتحدث معها لاحقاً
Chen.
‫تشين
Someone is making trouble inside.
‫هناك شخص في الداخل
I can't handle it.
لا يمكن التعامل معها
Wait here.
انتظر هنا
Don't touch the bag.
لا تلمس الكيس
The water on it is dirty.
الماء في الأعلى متسخ
It's not clean.
غير نظيف
You must give us an explanation.
يجب أن تعطينا تفسيرا
Calm down.
لا تقلق لا تقلق
Ask your boss to come out.
اطلب من رئيسك الخروج
Wait here.
انتظر هنا
I'll go in and take a look.
سأدخل وألقي نظرة
What are you looking at?
إلى ماذا تنظر
Fix it!
إصلاحها بسرعة
Why did you buy two big fish?
لماذا اشتريت سمكتين كبيرة
Isn't there a small one too?
‫أليس هناك سمكة صغيرة
Uncle Lu said
‫قال العم لو
he was scared you might want to eat a big fish
‫أخشى أنك تريد أكل السمك الكبير
and we didn't have one.
لا
Here.
تعال
Sir.
سيدي
Can you
هل يمكنك مساعدتنا
get us some warm water?
أحضر لنا وعاء من الماء الساخن
Okay. You go in first.
حسنًا، يمكنكم الدخول
I'll get you some water.
سأحضر لكم الماء
Okay, thank you.
حسنا شكرا
Thank you.
شكرا لك
You're welcome.
لا داعي للشكر يا آنسة
I'm happy that you came to chat with me.
تحدثي معي أنا سعيد
Come here more often.
تعال دائما في المستقبل
She will come often.
ستأتي دائما في المستقبل
I'll get going then.
سأذهب الآن
Go ahead.
تفضل
Wash your hands.
اغسل يديك
Sister-in-law?
زوجة أخي
Hai Dong?
هاي دونغ
We've finally met.
أخيرا رأيتك
Meng Xiaoshan told me about you.
‫سمعت منغ شياو شان تقول عنك
Lu Chen told me about you.
‫سمعت لو تشين يقول عنك
But I didn't get to see you.
‫لا أستطيع رؤيتك على أي حال
When did you get here?
متى أتيت
In the morning,
في الصباح
around ten o’clock.
‫أكثر من العاشرة
Lu Chen didn't tell me. He's hiding you from me.
‫لو تشين يختبئ عنك ولم يخبرني
If he'd told me,
‫إذا أخبرني
I'd have come immediately.
سيأتي على الفور
Wait a minute.
انتظر
There are some punks outside
هناك بعض الأشواك في الخارج
causing trouble.
يسبب المشاكل هناك
I'll go take a look.
سأذهب لأرى
I'll get rid of the water for you.
سأحضر لك الماء
Okay.
حسنا
Take this away too.
خذ هذا من أجلي
You're not leaving tonight, right?
ألن تغادر الليلة؟
Stay for dinner.
ابق لتناول الطعام
I'm staying.
لا
I'll sleep at Meng Xiaoshan's place tonight.
‫اسكن في منزل منغ شياو شان في المساء‬
That's good.
هذا جيد
The fish jumped out just now.
لقد خرجت هذه السمكة للتو
Qin Xiaonan and I got dirty
أنا و تشين شياو نان
when we put it back in.
إذا وضعناها في الداخل سوف تلوث
Let's go.
هيا
Let's go cook.
اذهب لطهي الطعام
Is everything okay at the garage?
كيف الحال   أمر غرفة العربة
It's nothing.
لا بأس
Who do you think I am?
ماذا أفعل
I got nervous and forgot.
نسيت عندما كنت متوترة
Go
اذهب
and do your workbook.
لنصنع كتاب التدريب
If we don't go,
إذا لم نذهب
shouldn't we tell your mother
هل يجب أن
in person?
أن تخبر والدتك
There's no need.
لا داعي
I'll tell her myself.
سأخبرها بنفسي
How do you want to eat it?
كيف تريد أن تأكل
What kind of fish is this?
ما هذا السمك؟
Mandarin fish.
سمكة سلور
It's expensive.
سمكة سلور غالية جدا
How expensive can a fish be?
كم الثمن من السمك؟
How do you want it?
كيف نأكل
I want squirrel fish.
سمك السلور والفئرر
You're still as picky as when you were young.
كما كنت صغيرًا
Don't you think it's troublesome?
لا تعتقد أن هذا مزعج
Hai Dong.
هاي دونغ
Let's eat together when you're free.
هل لديك وقت لتناول الطعام؟
Business has been booming lately.
لقد عملنا بشكل كبير مؤخرًا
Don't forget about us.
لا تنسينا
Go away.
اذهب اذهب اذهب
Hurry up.
اذهب بسرعة
Don't do anything stupid again.
لا ترتكب أي أخطاء في المستقبل
Hai Dong.
هاي دونغ
Buy a packet of cornstarch for me!
اشتري لي كيس من المسحوق
Okay.
حسنا
What are you doing in front of my hotel?
ماذا تفعل عند باب فندق
You want to borrow money?
هل اقترضت المال
No, I'm buying cornstarch.
لا أنا أشتري مسحوق
Who can make you run errands for them?
‫من يمكنه أن يستخدمك؟
Chen. Who else could it be?
‫تشين، من غيره؟
He's cooking?
‫إنه يطبخ
Who is he hosting?
لمن؟
Your sister, Gui Xiao.
أختك "غوي شياو"
She's back?
لقد عادت الفتاة
Tell her that
ساعدني في إخبارها
I'll keep the door open for her tonight
سأبقي لها الباب الليلة
at my parents' place.
عند والدي
Okay.
حسنا
I'll go in first.
سأدخل أولا
I'm so busy.
مشغول جدا
Here.
تعال
Check if it's too salty.
تذوقي هل مالح
It's not.
لا مالح
It's really fresh.
طازج جدا
Come on.
مزعج
How did you do it?
كيف فعلت ذلك
It opened just like that?
‫فتحت بسرعة‬
Take it easy.
اعتني بنفسك
Don't hurt yourself.
لا تؤذي
I have a cousin
لدي ابنة عمي
who's in a SWAT team.
إنها شرطية خاصة
She even trained to smash bricks
لقد تدربت بشكل خاص
with her bare hands.
تقطع الطوب بيدها
Do you know how to do it?
‫هل تستطيعين كسر الطوب بيديك‬
I've never trained for it.
لم أتدرب من قبل
I'm not good at that.
لا تجيد هذا
But I once
لكن في السابق
mentored a team member
أحضرت عضو في الفريق
who liked to do it.
أحب هذا
He had a stack of them lined up.
قطع قطعة
I think he must have smashed
ربما
dozens of them in a row.
يمكن أن تقطع عشرات
That's great.
جيد جدا
We were waiting for you.
أنتظرك فقط
I've bought the stuff.
لقد اشتريت الأشياء
I've also prepared
النبيذ والعاطفة
alcohol and my sentimentality.
أنا أيضاً مستعدة
We're just waiting for your dish.
سأنتظر أطباقك
Let me have a good cry.
دعني أبكي
I'll go cook.
سأطبخ
I saw his mother just now.
‫لقد رأيت والدته للتو
Lu Chen’s mom came?
‫هل ستأتي أم لو تشين
It was most likely that aunt-in-law
‫ربما كانت غرفة المالية
from the finance office who asked her to come.
زوجة عمك
My mom told me that
‫سمعت أمي تقول
when Lu Chen was three,
‫عندما كان لو تشين في الثالثة من عمره
he was punished and scolded by his dad
‫عاقبه والده على الوقوف والتوبيخ
during Chinese New Year.
‫في عيد الربيع
It was just because Lu Chen
‫بسبب لو تشين
had said something wrong.
‫خطأ
He stood beside the dining table
يقف بجانب الطاولة
for a whole night.
‫وقفت طوال الليل
Lu Chen’s mother wanted to see Lu Chen,
‫أرادت والدة لو تشين زيارة لو تشين
but his aunt-in-law didn't let her.
‫لا تسمح زوجة عمه
Lu Chen's father
‫والد لو تشين
favored sons over daughters.
‫كان يحب الرجال والنساء من قبل
He used to hit his sister whenever he got drunk.
تضرب أخته بمجرد أن ثملت
In the end,
‫والنتيجة
Lu Chen would deliberately provoke his father.
‫قام لو تشين بإزعاج والده عمداً
He saved his sister many times.
‫أنقذت أخته مرات عديدة
Now, he's finally grown up.
وأخيرا كبرت
It wasn't easy.
ليس سهلا
By the way,
بالمناسبة
are you two ready to make up?
هل أنتما مستعدان للتصالح؟
No.
لا
We're just friends.
صديق عادي
Take care.
أنتما بخير
if you two are happy.
سأكون سعيدة
I've brought him back for you.
لقد أحضرته لك
Make him drink more water.
أعطيه المزيد من الماء
Keep an eye on him tonight.
راقبه في المساء
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
Sister-in-law.
زوجة أخي
Get in.
اصعدي
Let's meet another day.
لنجتمع في يوم آخر
Gui Xiao?
عودوا إلى شياو
I'm Hai Jianfeng.
أنا هاي جيان فنغ
Do you remember me?
هل تتذكرني؟
Of course.
هراء
Wait.
لا
I was in Dalian a couple of days ago,
كنت في دا ليان قبل يومين
when they talked about having a class reunion.
قالوا أن حفلة زملاء الدراسة
I thought it was a pity that I couldn't see you.
من المؤسف أنني لم أراك
You...
أنت
Hai Jianfeng.
هاي جيان فينج
You're not allowed to have designs on Gui Xiao anymore.
‫توقف عن التفكير في عودتك
She's Chen's wife now.
‫إنها زوجة أخيك تشين الآن
What are you talking about?
‫عمّ تتحدثين؟
I was just excited
عندما رأيت زملائي القدامى
to see an old classmate.
أنا متحمسة
Come on.
يكفي
Let me tell you.
أقول لك
This brother of mine
أخي
fell in love with your wife
منذ بداية المدرسة
on the first day of secondary school.
في بداية المدرسة
You wouldn't even believe it.
لا أجرؤ على قول ذلك
Even now, he still has
الآن هناك صورة
a photo of Gui Xiao
صورة عودة إلى النهار
by his bedside.
ضعها على رأس السرير
It's been there since graduation!
منذ التخرج حتى الآن
My brother is talking nonsense.
أخي يتحدث هراء
G- Gui Xiao.
‫غوي شياو
You are Chen look good together.
‫أنت والأخ تشين بخير
It wasn't easy for you two.
‫ليس سهلاً
Y- You look good together.
جيد جدا
Hasn't everyone had a crush?
‫من لم يقع في حب سري، أليس كذلك؟
If Lu Chen hadn’t come back,
‫إذا لم يعد لو تشين
you might have stood a chance.
‫ربما لديك فرصة
Brother, you...
أخي أنت
Alright.
حسنا حسنا
Let's stop talking.
لا تتكلم لا تتكلم
Why did you drink so much?
لماذا شربت كثيرا
Mom.
أمي
Let me introduce them to you, Gui Xiao.
جوى شياو دعني أقدم لك
This is my sister.
هذه أختي
This is my mom.
هذه أمي
We'll go in first.
سندخل أولا
-Okay. -Go back.
حسنًا، عد بسرعة
♫Easy come, easy go♫
فلنمشي بحرية
Alright.
حسنا
Where is the photo?
أين الصور
Let me see.
‫دعني أرى
Chen.
‫تشين
My brother is drunk.
‫أخي ثمل
He was talking nonsense.
هذا هراء
I put it away a long time ago.
لم أضعه منذ وقت طويل
I'll get it now.
سأحضرها الآن
I'll get it for you now.
سأحضرها لك الآن
W- Wait for me.
انتظرني
There's no need!
لا داعي
It's quite pretty.
جميلة جدا
I don't even have this photo.
ليس لدي هذه الصورة
Thank you for safekeeping it for me.
شكرا لك على الاحتفاظ بها
You're welcome.
لا بأس
We'll leave now.
سنغادر الآن
Go back in.
لنعد
I was so young back then.
كان صغيرًا جدًا في ذلك الوقت
How did he get your photo?
كيف كان لديه صورك
I don't know.
لا أعرف
I remember the teacher
أتذكر هذه الصورة
taking this photo.
التقطها المعلم
Maybe he asked the teacher for it.
ربما طلب من المعلم
He's quite thoughtful.
إنه لطيف جدًا
If you hadn't come to Qining,
لولا مجيئك إلى تشي نينغ
I wouldn't have come back.
لما عدت الآن
The last time I went to Qining,
المرة السابقة ذهبت إلى تشي نينغ
even if I hadn't lost my car,
حتى لو لم أفقد السيارة
I would have gone to find you.
سأبحث عنك
I asked Huang Ting for your phone number
قبل عامين
two years ago.
من هوانغ تينغ
I can even recite it backwards.
يمكنني حفظ رقم العكس
Recite it for me.
‫احفظها دعني أسمع
I've forgotten now.
نسيت الآن
You forgot it once you saw me?
نسيت عندما تراني
Call me before going to bed.
اتصل بي قبل النوم
Bye.
سأذهب
I was worried that you'll sleep at the garage.
كنت قلقة أنك تعيشين في مصنع إصلاح السيارة
There are too many prying eyes there.
هناك الكثير من الناس
Come to think of it,
‫من الواضح
Lu Chen is quite sensible.
‫لو تشين عاقل
He really sent you here.
‫أرسلك إلى هنا
It's no different from when you dated
لا تختلف كثيرا
when you were young.
في الحب
You still can't bear to part with him.
لا أريد الانفصال
It's like you earn money
انظر أكثر
by taking one more look at him.
مثل كسب الكثير
My parents are not home today.
أبي وأمي ليس في المنزل اليوم
It's just the two of us.
نحن فقط
I saw his mother today.
‫رأيت والدته اليوم
She doesn’t look like Lu Chen at all.
‫لا تشبه لو تشين على الإطلاق
I didn’t recognize her.
‫لم تتعرف عليه
His parents are hard to get along with.
ليس من السهل التعامل مع سيدهم
I can't be bothered to deal with them
شخص ذكي مثلي
even though I'm so sociable.
لا أريد التعامل معه
You
أنت
better not see them often.
من الأفضل أن تراني قليلا في المستقبل
Did you talk to him
هل تحدثتم
after sending Hai Dong back?
هل تحدثتم؟
No.
لا
You've cleared all the obstacles.
تم إزالة العقبات لكم
Hurry up if you want to do something about it.
ماذا تريدون أن تفعلوا أسرعوا
I'll take my time.
ببطء
Hello.
ألو
I regret it.
أنا نادم
I should have stayed with you a little longer.
يجب أن أبقى معك لفترة أطول
We haven't talked properly
بعد عودتك
since you came back.
لم نتحدث بشكل جيد
You want to see me?
هل تريد رؤيتي؟
I haven't left.
لم أغادر بعد
But Meng Xiaoshan is asleep now.
‫لكن الآن منغ شياو شان نائمة‬
I can’t go out.
لا يمكنني الخروج
The dog is indoors today.
اليوم الكلب في الغرفة
The guest room is on the other side on the second floor?
الغرفة في الخلف من الطابق الثاني
Yes.
نعم
I remember the plot behind this house
أتذكر أن الفناء الخلفي
has been sold.
تم بيعها
They're building a new house there,
تريد بناء منزل جديد
right?
أليس كذلك
♫I'll sing for you♫
لا أعرف
Meng Xiaoshan didn't tell me
‫لم تخبرني منغ شياو شان‬
about her neighbors.
عن جيرها
What about it?
ما الخطب؟
♫I believe you can do it♫
انتظر
Do you see it?
هل رأيت؟
Yes.
نعم
Aren't you afraid of being seen?
ألا تخشى أن يكتشفك أحد
What's wrong? Did you fall?
ماذا حدث؟ هل سقطت؟
Someone is coming.
شخص ما قادم
I'm leaving.
سأذهب
Sleep early.
‫نم مبكرًا
Uncle Lu.
‫العم لو
I thought you weren't coming back
‫اعتقدت أنك
to sleep tonight.
الليلة
Where else could  go?
أين أسكن إذا لم تعد
Have you gotten used to it here?
هل تعودت على الانتقال إلى هنا
Do you miss home?
هل تشتاق إلى المنزل
I've been here for so long.
لقد جئت إلى هنا منذ عدة أيام
Why did you only ask me tonight?
لماذا لم تسألي هذا المساء
Aunt Gui Xiao...
العمة جو شياو
Uncle.
عمي
What do you want to ask?
ماذا تريد أن تسأل؟
Go to sleep.
نامي
What has Aunt Gui Xiao
عمتك جوى شياو
been doing recently?
ماذا تفعل مؤخرا
I didn't have time to ask.
لم يكن لدي الوقت لأسألك
Do you know about her job?
هل تعرف
Is there anything wrong with her work?
ما الخطأ في عملها؟
Is it against the rules?
هل انتهكت قوانينكم؟
No.
لا
I just want to know.
أريد فقط أن أعرف
Just ask Aunt Gui Xiao.
اسأل العمة جو شياو مباشرة
It's 2 a.m.
الآن الساعة الثانية صباحا
How do I ask?
كيف تسأل
Ask her tomorrow.
اسأل غدا
I'm not sure.
لا أعرف
I think she's an investor.
يبدو أنه يعمل في الاستثمار
She has money and looks for projects everywhere.
ويبحث عن المشروع في كل مكان بالمال
She told her colleagues she was investing in...
وأخبرت زملائها أنها استثمار
in educational...
التعليم الاستثماري
educational...
التعليم
new energy?
الطاقة الجديدة
I think so.
يبدو ذلك
Go to sleep.
نامي
Your hand.
يدك
Get up.
استيقظ
You're going to be late.
تأخرت
Stop it.
لا تعبث
I’m sleepy.
‫نعسان
Lu Chen is here
‫لو تشين
to pick you up to go to school.
‫أتيت لأخذك إلى المدرسة
I want...
أريد
My flight is at twelve.
طائرتي في الساعة الثانية عشرة
Let me sleep until eight.
دعني أنام حتى الساعة الثامنة
Why would I lie to you?
‫لماذا أخدعك
Lu Chen brought breakfast.
‫اشتر لو تشين الفطور
Morning.
‫صباح الخير
I bought it for you.
اشتريتها لك
The auntie outside the school gate
في السابق عند بوابة المدرسة
opened her own store.
عند بوابة المدرسة
It tastes the same.
الطعم القديم
It's still hot.
ما زالت ساخنة
Have you eaten?
هل أكلت
I ate at the garage.
أكلت للتو في مصنع الصيانة
I didn't have time to eat on the way.
لم يكن لدينا وقت لتناول الطعام في الطريق
I'm going back to work soon.
سأعود إلى المكتب على الفور
There's a secret mission.
مهمة سرية
I won't be able to use my phone for a while.
لا أستطيع مشاهدة الهاتف هذه الأيام
The nature of my work is a bit different.
شخصيتي في العمل مميزة
I become uncontactable at times
غالبا ما لا أستطيع العثور على شخص
and cannot explain anything.
ولا يمكن تفسير أي شيء
I'm telling you in advance
يجب أن أخبرك مسبقا
so you don't overthink this.
لا تفكري كثيرا
Well...
إذن
I'll be off now.
سأذهب
You're still here?
ألن تذهب بعد؟
It was so busy
عدت هذه المرة
this time.
مشغول
Let's talk properly
عندما تعود في رحلة عمل
when you come back from your business trip.
لنتحدث
About what?
عن ماذا
Your job.
عملك
My job.
عملي
My family background.
وضع عائلتي الأساسية
The situation
وهذه المرة
after my transfer back.
هذه المرة
My salary
وضع الراتب
and my personal assets.
وملكاتي الشخصية
When we were in school,
عندما كنت في المدرسة
I didn't tell you much about these.
لم أتحدث معك كثيرا في هذا الجانب
I want to make them clear this time.
أريد أن أوضح هذه المرة
You're thoughtful.
تفكيرك دقيق
You should make them clear.
يجب أن نتحدث بوضوح
Of course,
بالطبع
if you
إذا كنتم فقط
just want to date,
تريد أن تقعا في الحب
then it's not necessary.
لا داعي لذلك
There's no need to say.
لا داعي لقول
It's good to retain
حافظ على بعض الإحساس الغامض
a bit of the mystery.
هذا جيد
Go to work.
اذهبي إلى العمل بسرعة
I'm going too after I eat.
سأذهب أيضًا بعد الأكل
Okay.
حسنا
We'll talk about it later.
سنتحدث لاحقًا
I’m leaving.
‫سأذهب أولاً
Does your dad know Lu Chen is back?
‫هل يعرف والدك أن لو تشين عاد؟
I don’t want to tell him.
‫لا أريد إخباره
I thought
اعتقدت
you would wait for me at the airport.
أنك تنتظرني في المطار
I saw that I still had some time,
أعتقد أنه لا يزال هناك بعض الوقت
so I came back to attend the weekly meeting.
ستعود لعقد اجتماع أسبوع أولا
You two. Tell me
أنتما، تعالي وتخبراني
about your recent projects.
مشاريعكما الأخيرة
Pass me the agenda.
أعطني اجتماع الأسبوع
You go first.
تكلم أولا
I'll tell you one by one.
سأقول واحدا تلو الآخر
Okay.
‫حسناً
They insist that the shareholders
‫أصروا على أن مؤتمر المساهمين
should have veto rights.
‫أن لديهم حق الإنكار
I told them
‫سأخبرهم‬
I can't promise them something like that,
لا يمكنني اتخاذ القرار
and that the bosses on both sides
يجب أن ننتظر الرئيس الكبير من الجانبين
need to discuss this directly.
تحدث مباشرة
Make an appointment
يمكنك تحديد موعد
for a teleconference with Mr. Wu.
وقت الاجتماع على الهاتف من السيد وو
After the secretary confirms it,
بعد تأكيد السكرتير
email the other party
وأخبر الطرف الآخر عبر البريد الإلكتروني
and CC Mr. Wu and me.
أرسلها لي أنا والسيد وو
Also, they think
وهم يظنون
the minimum of 13% of shares
13% من الأسهم
is too low.
منخفض جدا
They're requesting a directly proportionate capital increase.
طلب زيادة نسبة
We have been dealing with this
هذا السؤال
for two weeks.
لقد كنت مترددة لمدة أسبوعين
How about this?
هكذا
Delete the clause on the contract
يمكنك حذف
that precludes capital increase
في العقد
and proceed with the negotiations.
استمر في التعامل معهم
Okay.
حسنا
The bottom line I'm giving you
الحد الأدنى الذي أعطيتك إياه
is that we can add a clause for capital increase
يمكن زيادة شروط الاستثمار
into the contract,
في العقد
but it cannot stipulate any specific requirements.
لكن لا يمكن تحديد متطلبات محددة
For instance, terms like
مثل النسبة
"directly proportionate"
هكذا لا يمكن
must not appear in the contract.
في العقد
Remember.
تذكر
We can only
الحد الأدنى
reveal our bottom line
‫يجب أن يكون أكثر من ثلاث جولات على الأقل‬
after at least three rounds of negotiation.
حتى تظهر
Okay.
حسنًا
Let me teach you.
سأعلمك
Every time the negotiations reach a stalemate,
‫في كل مرة لا يمكن سحبها‬
just say,
فقط
"I can't make this decision.
لا يمكنني اتخاذ القرار
Let me ask my boss."
بعد أن أسأل رئيسي
Then, answer them the next day.
ثم أجيبه في اليوم التالي
If that doesn't work, tell them,
إذا لم تستطيعي إقناعه
"My boss is very unaccommodating.
رئيسي صعب التعامل معه
She's very difficult to talk to.
من الصعب التحدث
I'll try to persuade her again."
سأبذل قصارى جهدي لإقناعها
Yes.
نعم نعم
Blame it all on me.
كل هذا علي
I am here
الرئيس
to act as your shield.
هو الدفاع عنكم
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
I won't take it to heart
‫لن أهتم
no matter how many bad things you say about me.
لن أهتم به
Dad.
أبي
I'm at the airport.
أنا في المطار
My dad is here.
أبي هنا